3830 Jackson street, APT L-24

Raleigh, NC 27607

Mobile phone: (980) 339-9698

Email: hi@igibek.com

Github: https://github.com/igibek Website: https://igibek.com

IGIBEK KOISHYBAYEV

CAREER SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with more than 6 years of experience. As a full-stack developer, I designed, developed, tested, and deployed several projects, which are listed below. I have experience working with different technology stacks, such as LAMP, MEAN, and ASP.NET stack. I am familiar with continuous development (CD) and continuous integration (CI). I have deployed web applications to Microsoft Azure, DigitalOcean and other hosting providers. I have experience in configuring web servers, such as Nginx, Apache and DNS.

SKILLS

General: Full-stack Developer, Software Engineering, DevOps, Web Development, Security, OOP, Source Control, Cloud Technologies, Continuous Development, Continuous Integration, Debugging, Testing, Unit Test, Automation, Database, Coding standards, UML, System Design and Architecture, Writing/reading documentations, Time management, Focusing

Programming: C#, Javascript, Php, Python, C, C++, Java, Shell script, SQL

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET WebAPI, Laravel, Restful, Node.js, Git, MSSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Vagrant, Docker, Kubernetes, MS Azure, Redis, Vue.js, Rest API, Postgre, ASP.NET, Ansible, Kubernetes, npm, SSH, Apache, Nginx, Flask, uWSGI, PWA, Android, iOS, Entity Framework, LINQ, JekvII

EXPERIENCE

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC — *Graduate Research Assistant*

AUGUST 2017 - PRESENT

- Right now I am working as part of Wolfpack Security and Privacy Lab. My main research area is Node.is security.
- I helped to organize annual Hackpack CTF competition for undergraduates in April 2018. Four of my proposed challenges were selected to be part of the competition.

International Information Technologies University, Almaty, Kazakhstan — Senior Lecturer

JANUARY 2016 - AUGUST 2017

- I was the first senior lecturer, who introduced "Cybersecurity" elective course for undergraduate students, oriented to teach students with security basics by teaching them how to hack.
- I also was part of the organizing committee of "UNICEF Children" and "KazakhTelecom" hackathons.
- I was advisor for 2 student teams for their senior project, that they both defended successfully.

Zerek Group, Almaty, Kazakhstan — Software Engineer & Administrator

MAY 2013 - PRESENT

- I was responsible for the whole IT infrastructure of the company. When I was working in the company, I transferred all in-house solutions to a cloud, which improved availability of services and productivity of employees, because they started using already familiar technologies.
- I developed online russian-kazakh-russian dictionary, which increased quality of translated works.
- Also I developed Zerek Cabinet, which helps customers to manage their orders. Customer can see and control the full workflow of translation, which increased the customer engagement. This product also helped Zerek Group to gain a new customer segments in Kazakhstan.

Boston University, Boston, MA – Teaching Assistant

SEPTEMBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

• After successfully completing "EC521: Cybersecurity", I started to work as a TA in next semester.

EDUCATION

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC — PhD in Computer Science

AUGUST 2017 - PRESENT

Boston University, Boston, MA – Master of Science in Computer Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JANUARY 2016

International Information Technologies University, Almaty, Kazakhstan — Bachelor in Information Systems

SEPTEMBER 2009 - JULY 2013

PROJECTS

Tusopsi.com (http://tusopsi.com) (under-development)

Description: The web application for medical exam preparation. Currently under development.

Responsibility: Full stack development from designing to deployment. Because we decided to use DigitalOcean as a platform to deploy, I am responsible for configuring VMs (Nginx, security, MySQL)

Technologies used: HTML, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Asp.net Core MVC 5, C#, MySQL, Git, Visual Code, DigitalOcean, Nginx, Vue.js, REST API, Entity Framework

Topuniver (https://topuniver.com)

Description: The web application for rating the universities in Kazakhstan.

Technologies used: Vue.js, JavaScript, HTML, Bootstrap, Laravel, Php 7, Apache, Visual Code, Vue.js, REST API

TeaTalks (https://teatalks.me)

Description: The static blogging website generated using Jekyll.

Technologies used: HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Jekyll

Zerek Cabinet (disabled) (proof-of-work can be shown upon request)

Description: Web application, that helps to manage work orders (translating documents) of company.

Technologies used: MS Azure, ASP.NET MVC 5, C#, MS SQL, Azure Storage, Git, HTML, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, REST API, Entity Framework, LINQ

Zerek Dictionary (https://dictionary.zerek.kz)

Description: Online translator from kazakh to russian and vice versa.

Technologies used: Php, MySql, HTML, JavaScript, Git, Jquery

Zerek Flashcard (available in Windows Store)

Description: Windows Phone 8 flashcard application for GRE preparation.

Technologies used: C#, Windows Phone, XAML, Visual Studio, Bitbucket, Git

iFocus (available in Windows Store)

Description: Windows 10 Universal Windows Application to help users to concentrate on task using

pomodoro technique.

Technologies used: C#, UWP, Visual Studio, XAML, Windows 10

Tenge (available in Play market)

Description: Android application for current exchange rate of Kazakhstan's national currency.

Technologies used: Java, Android Studio

Baseball Catcher (available in Play market)

Description: Android game.

Technologies used: Java, Android Studio, Unity

Random Choice (available in Play market)

Description: Android application for selecting randomly from given options.

Technologies used: Java, Android Studio

DSign (available in Play market)

Description: Android application for digitally signing PDF files.

Technologies used: Java, Android Studio

Latynga (available in Chrome Web market)

Description: Google Chrome extension to change website text from Cyrillic letters to Latin letters.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Git, Chrome API

Safe (open sourced in Github)

Description: Android application to generate one-time passwords every 30 seconds depending on token. This OTP can be used as two-factor authentication to improve security.

Technologies used: Java, Android Studio